

Berlin/Germany

□ (+49) 176 76494837 | ■ utku@turunc.me | 📅 utku.turunc.me | 🗖 utkuturunc | 🛅 utkuturunc

## **Summary** <sub>-</sub>

Software Engineer of three years with additional three years of experience in full-stack web development from freelance projects.

Professionally, I have been developing backends in Play Framework (Scala), Spring Boot (Kotlin) and Express/Koa (NodeJS). I have experience in developing and designing microservices and I also have experience in AWS, Google Cloud Platform, Docker and Kubernetes as I've been taking active responsibilities in DevOPS for several projects.

Spending two years at a software house enabled me to work on several different projects allowing me to get experienced with various technologies and every part of the software development cycle from design to deployment. I have been mainly focused on backend development but due to my freelance projects and personal interests, I am also fluent in ReactJS and it's ecosystem including but not limited to React-Router, Redux and GraphQL.

My current technology of choice is Scala, namely Play Framework. I am actively trying to develop a more functional style of programming.

# Work Experience \_\_\_\_\_

**Zalando SE** Berlin, Germany

SOFTWARE ENGINEER Feb. 2019 - Present

- Worked on a microservice in Scala for a new architecture built for a large scale logistics management system.
- Created multiple tooling, especially one for automated e2e testing on CI/CD pipelines.
- Provided maintenance and support for legacy systems.

McMakler GmbH. Berlin, Germany

SOFTWARE ENGINEER Aug. 2018 - Feb. 2019

- Worked as a NodeJS backend developer for in house built CRM system.
- Developed and maintained microservices.

Istanbul, Turkey

**Valensas** 

Jul. 2016 - Jul. 2018 SOFTWARE ENGINEER

- Gained experience leading small to medium sized projects.
- · Worked as backend engineer, focusing on chatbots.
- · Designed a chatbot framework that can manage conversation states, execute timed jobs, integrate with other web services, use machine learning and natural language processing in order to understand user input.
- Worked for a large scale banking project, designing and developing microservices

**Freelance** Istanbul, Turkey

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER Jan. 2013 - Jul. 2016

- Worked on several small to medium scale freelance projects as a full stack developer.
- Stack of choice is NodeJS (Koa) or Play Framework (Scala) + ReactJS with GraphQL.
- · Mostly took part on the backend and admin ui.
- · Completed a directory of blogs, truck rental and route planning app, motorcycle renting and tour reservation app, a donation app for a non-profit, a chat base party game.

### Skills

**Programming - Strong** Scala, Typescript, JavaScript, NodeJS, Kotlin

**Programming - Familiar** Java, Python, Spark, CoreNLP, Machine Learning, Natural Language Processing

Web Development Play Framework, Akka, Spring Boot, ReactJS, Redux, GraphQL, Express, Koa, HTML5, CSS, REST

**DevOPS** AWS, Google Cloud Engine, Docker, Kubernetes, Linux, Microservices

Database Redis, PostgreSQL, MongoDB

**Electronics** SPICE, MagicVLSI, IRSIM, Matlab, Arduino, C, C++, Filter Design, VHDL, Analog Circuit Design, MEMS

### **Presentations**

### Turkey Artificial Intelligence Initiative (turkiye.ai)

Istanbul, Turkey

Presenter for Valensas Oct. 2017

• A talk about the usage of artificial intelligence in our projects

### **Education**

### İTÜ (Istanbul Technical University) (3.95/4)

Istanbul, Turkey

B.S. IN ELECTRONICS AND COMMUNICATION ENGINEERING

Sep. 2012 - Jun. 2013

Transferred to Boğaziçi University at the end of the first year

### Boğaziçi University (3.24/4)

Istanbul, Turkey

B.S. IN ELECTRICAL AND ELECTRONICS ENGINEERING

Sep. 2013 - Jun. 2016

- Completed electronics specialization
- · Grade is not inclusive of first year

## **Projects**

### **Logistics Management System**

Berlin, Germany

SOFTWARE ENGINEER - ZALANDO SE

Feb. 2019 - Present

• Development of a microservice for a very large scale logistics backend

#### **Real Estate CRM System**

Berlin, Germany

SOFTWARE ENGINEER - MCMAKLER GMBH.

Aug. 2018 - Feb. 2019

• Development and maintenance of microservices powering Immoforce, an internal CRM system for the company.

### **Tosla - P2P Banking Application by Akbank**

Istanbul, Turkey

SOFTWARE ENGINEER - VALENSAS

Feb. 2018 - Jul. 2018

- · Developed several microservices, namely core banking and social feeds for a modern peer to peer banking application
- Set up Kubernetes configurations and deployment pipelines.
- Project uses Spring Boot and Hibernate for core banking, Scala (Akka) for social feeds

Valensas VoT Istanbul, Turkey

SOFTWARE ENGINEER - VALENSAS

Jul. 2016 - Mar. 2018

- Valensas VoT is a complete customizable chatbot solution that includes conversation management, natural language processing in English and Turkish, machine learning and scheduled tasks.
- Designed and developed the framework for this project that was used in several other projects.

### **Akbank Assistant - Akbank Chatbot**

Istanbul, Turkey

SOFTWARE ENGINEER - VALENSAS

Sep. 2017 - May. 2018

- · Developed a chatbot for Akbank which can be used to transfer money and pay invoices, one of the largest banks in Turkey.
- The project was written as microservices in TypeScript and Scala (Play Framework, Spark and CoreNLP) and deployed to Akbank datacenters on Linux.
- Project has been released with a TV commercial and printed press coverage.

#### **Boti - Turkish Airlines Chatbot**

Istanbul, Turkey

SOFTWARE ENGINEER - VALENSAS

Feb. 2017 - Sep. 2017

- Developed a chatbot for Turkish Airlines, a star alliance member and flag carrier airline of Turkey. The bot can be used to buy tickets, select seats, check-in, query flight statuses and more.
- The project was written as 4 microservices in TypeScript and Scala (Play Framework, Spark and CoreNLP) and deployed to AWS.

### **Hepsichat - Hepsiburada Chatbot**

Istanbul, Turkey

Jul. 2016 - Dec. 2016

SOFTWARE ENGINEER - VALENSAS

SOFTWARE ENGINEER - VALENSAS

Nov. 2016 - Feb. 2017

- Developed a customer support chatbot for the largest e-commerce platform in Turkey, Hepsiburada.
- The chatbot greets users, collects information and solves specific issues, if it cannot resolve the issue it redirects the users to human agents, saving time and resources.
- The project was written in TypeScript and Scala (Play Framework, Spark and CoreNLP) and deployed to AWS Lambda.

AskTim - Chatbot Istanbul, Turkey

- Developed a Slack bot that is integrated with several analytics providers such as Mixpanel and Google Analytics.
- The bot is able to process natural language and produce visual reports combining data from different sources.
- The project was written in Scala using Play Framework and CoreNLP and deployed to AWS.

NOVEMBER 3, 2019 UTKU TURUNC · RÉSUMÉ 2